Guide to the World War II Pamphlet Collection 1937-1991 (bulk 1939-1945)
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana-Missoula
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1942; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1942. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box OS 20/3)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1942; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1942. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box OS 20/4)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1942; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1942. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box OS 20/5)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1943; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1943. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box OS 21/1)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1943; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1943. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box OS 21/2)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1943; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1943. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box OS 21/3)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1943; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1943. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box OS 22/1)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1943; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1943. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box OS 22/2)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1943; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1943. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box OS 22/3)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1944; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1944. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 9/5)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1944; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1944. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 10/1)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1944; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1944. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 10/2)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1944; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1944. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 10/3)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1944; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1944. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 10/4)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1945; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1945. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 10/5)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1945; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1945. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 10/6)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1945; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1945. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 11/1)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1945; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1945. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 11/2)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1946; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1946. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 11/3)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1946; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1946. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 11/4)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1946; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1946. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 11/5)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1946; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1946. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 11/6)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1946; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1946. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 11/7)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1947; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1947. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 12/1)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1947; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1947. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 12/2)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1948; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1948. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 12/3)
- India - Propaganda, British: War Effort (in English), 1940-1945 and undated; India and the War: A Summary of India's Contribution. New York: British Library of Information, 1940.; Dunbar, George, and William R. B. Birdwood. India at War: A Record and a Review, 1939-1940. London: H.M. Stationery Office, 1940.; India at War: June 1941. N.p., 1941.; India Shares Victory in the West. Washington: Government of India Information Services, 1945.; India's War Effort. New York: British Library of Information, n.d. (Box 12/4)
- Japan - Domestic Politics: Economics (in English), 1938-1940; East Asia Economic Intelligence Series: The Capital Market of Japan, No. 4. Tokyo: Japan Economic Federation, 1940.; Suma, Yakichirō. Economic Conditions in Japan. Philadelphia: The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1938. (Box 12/5)
- Japan - Foreign Relations: with the United States (in English), 1939; Facts About Trade Relations of the United States and Japan. Chicago: Japan Foreign Trade Bureau, 1939.; American-Japanese Trade and Treaty Abrogation: An Economic Analysis of the Possible Effects of the Abrogation of the American-Japanese Treaty of 1911 Upon American-Japanese Trade. San Francisco?: The Japanese Chamber of Commerce, 1939. (Box 12/6)
- Japan - Propaganda: Invasion of China (in English), 1937-1938; America and Japan's Manifest Destiny. Kyoto, Japan: Bussinessmen of Kyoto, 1937.; Why the Fighting in Shanghai [with plates and map]. Tokyo: Foreign Affairs Association of Japan, 1937.; Japanese Relief Work in the Occupied Areas. [with Plates and a Map.]. Tokyo: Foreign Affairs Association of Japan, 1938.; The Cases for Japan and China (Reprint from "Asia", November, 1937): Frank Arguments for Both Sides. Tokyo: Foreign Affairs Association of Japan, 1938. (Box 12/7)
- Japan - Propaganda: Invasion of China (in English), 1939-1940; Arita, Hachirō. Japan's Diplomacy: Its Aims and Principles As Outlined in the Speeches and Remarks by Hachiro Arita, Foreign Minister, at the 74th Session of the Imperial Diet, 1938-39. Tokyo: Japan Times and Mail, 1939.; Sekine, Gunpei. How to Build Up New East Asia. Tokyo: To-a Kensetsu Kyokai, 1940. (Box 12/8)
- Japan - Propaganda: "Japan-China Pictorial Primer" (in English), 1937-1938; What's It All About?, No. 1. Tokyo: Japan Pacific Association, 1937.; How About Giving Japan a Break?: Truth Will Out!, No. 2. Tokyo: Japan Pacific Association, 1937.; Do You Know That ...?: Fifty Questions on Current Topics, No. 3. Tokyo: Japan Pacific Association, 1938.; Japan's Problems, No. 4. Tokyo: Japan Pacific Association, 1938.; Are You Sure That-?, No. 5. Tokyo: Japan Pacific Association, 1938. (Box 12/9)
- Japan - Propaganda: Pictorials (in English), 1939; Hasegawa, Nyozekan. Girls of Japan. Tokyo: Japan Photo Service, 1939. (Box 12/10)
- Korea - Foreign Relations: with the United States (in English), 1945-1946; The Voice of Korea. Washington, D.C: The Institute, 1945-46. (A monthly, serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 12/11)
- Mexico - Domestic Politics: Labor (in English), 1944; Mexican Labor News. Mexico City: Press Dept. of the Workers University of Mexico, 1944. (A serial publication; only one issue available.) (Box 12/12)
- Mexico - Foreign Relations: "International Policy Popular Series" (in English), 1945; Our International Policy: Address broadcasted by Hon. Ezequiel Padilla, Secretary of Foreign Affairs on January 7th, during the "National Hour" of the Mexican Goverment. Mexico: Dept. of Foreign Affairs, 1945. (A serial publication; only one issue available.); Towards the Organization of the Coming Peace: Address, delivered by Hon. Ezequiel Padilla, Secretary of Foreign Affairs on the 22nd of February during the Inaugural Session of the Interamerican Conference on War and Peace Problems. Mexico: Dept. of Foreign Affairs, 1945. (A serial publication; only one issue available.); Our Contribution to the Cause of the Americas: Address delivered by Hon. Ezequiel Padilla, Secretary of Foreign Affairs on the 8th of March during the Closing Session of the Interamerican Conference on War and Peace Problems. Mexico: Dept. of Foreign Affairs, 1945. (A serial publication; only one issue available.); To the Mexicans in the United States: Addresses pronounced in commemoration of the Fifth of May in the city of Los angeles, California. Mexico: Dept. of Foreign Affairs, 1945. (A serial publication; only one issue available.); With the Mexican Laborers in the United States: Address Delivered on May 13 in the City of San Jose, California. Mexico: Dept. of Foreign Affairs, 1945. (A serial publication; only one issue available.) (Box 13/1)
- Mexico - News Coverage: "Mexico News" (in English), 1943-1945; Mexico News. Published Monthly by the International Press Service Bureau of the Department of State for Foreign Affairs. Mexico: Compania Editora Y Librera ARS, S, A., 1943-45. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 13/2)
- Netherlands - Colonialism (in English), 1945; Mook, Hubertus J. Past and Future in the Netherlands Indies. New York: Netherlands Information Bureau, 1945. (Box 13/3)
- Netherlands - Domestic Politics: Education (in English), 1942; Lourens, Marinus M. Education in the Netherlands. New York City: Netherlands Information Bureau, 1942. (Box 13/4)
- Netherlands - Foreign Politics (in English), 1943; Kleffens, Eelco N. The Foreign Policy of the Netherlands: Text of a Broadcast. New York City: Netherlands Information Bureau, 1943. (Box 13/5)
- Netherlands - Foreign Politics: Economics (in Dutch, English, French, and German), undated; Saint Lvca's Society, Rapenburg 83 Leiden: Catalogue 4. Leiden: St. Lvcas Soceity Antiquarian Booksellers, n.d. (This publication is a list of available books on the subjects of Political and Economic History, Economy, and Legal Sciences. There are a variety of books with English, German or French titles as well as Dutch. Many of the titles listed have to do with the years leading up to, after, or during World War II.) (Box 13/6)
- Netherlands - History (in English), 1939; Balluseck, Daniel J. Holland's House: A Nation Building a Home. Haarlem, Holland: Printed by J. Enschedé en zonen, 1939. (Box 13/7)
- Netherlands - News Coverage: "Knickerbocker Weekly" (in English), 1943; Knickerbocker Weekly. New York: Netherland Publishing Corporation, 1943. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 13/8)
- Netherlands - News Coverage: "Knickerbocker Weekly" (in English), 1944; Knickerbocker Weekly. New York: Netherland Publishing Corporation, 1944. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 13/9)
- Netherlands - News Coverage: "Knickerbocker Weekly" (in English), 1944; Knickerbocker Weekly. New York: Netherland Publishing Corporation, 1944. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 13/10)
- Netherlands - News Coverage: "Knickerbocker Weekly" (in English), 1944; Knickerbocker Weekly. New York: Netherland Publishing Corporation, 1944. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 13/11)
- Netherlands - News Coverage: "Knickerbocker Weekly" (in English), 1944; Knickerbocker Weekly. New York: Netherland Publishing Corporation, 1944. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 13/12)
- Netherlands - News Coverage: "Knickerbocker Weekly" (in English), 1945; Knickerbocker Weekly. New York: Netherland Publishing Corporation, 1945. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 13/13)
- Netherlands - News Coverage: "Knickerbocker Weekly" (in English), 1946; Knickerbocker Weekly. New York: Netherland Publishing Corporation, 1946. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 13/14)
- Netherlands - News Coverage: "Netherlands News" (in English), 1941; Netherlands News. New York: Netherlands Information Bureau, 1941. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 14/1)
- Netherlands - News Coverage: "Netherlands News" (in English), 1942; Netherlands News. New York: Netherlands Information Bureau, 1942. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 14/2)
- Netherlands - News Coverage: "Netherlands News" (in English), 1945; Netherlands News. New York: Netherlands Information Bureau, 1945. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 14/3)
- Netherlands - News Coverage: "Netherlands News" (in English), 1945; Netherlands News. New York: Netherlands Information Bureau, 1945. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 14/4)
- Netherlands - News Coverage: "Netherlands News Digest" (in English), 1942; Netherlands News Digest. New York: Netherlands Information Bureau, 1942. (A bi-monthly, serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 14/5)
- Netherlands - News Coverage: "Netherlands News Digest" (in English), 1942; Netherlands News Digest. New York: Netherlands Information Bureau, 1942. (A bi-monthly, serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 14/6)
- Netherlands - News Coverage: "Netherlands News Digest" (in English), 1943; Netherlands News Digest. New York: Netherlands Information Bureau, 1943. (A bi-monthly, serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 14/7)
- Netherlands - News Coverage: "Netherlands News Digest" (in English), 1943; Netherlands News Digest. New York: Netherlands Information Bureau, 1943. (A bi-monthly, serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 14/8)
- Netherlands - News Coverage: "Netherlands News Digest" (in English), 1943; Netherlands News Digest. New York: Netherlands Information Bureau, 1943. (A bi-monthly, serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 15/1)
- Netherlands - News Coverage: "Netherlands News Digest" (in English), 1944; Netherlands News Digest. New York: Netherlands Information Bureau, 1944. (A bi-monthly, serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 15/2)
- Netherlands - News Coverage: "Netherlands News Digest" (in English), 1944; Netherlands News Digest. New York: Netherlands Information Bureau, 1944. (A bi-monthly, serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 15/3)
- Netherlands - News Coverage: "Netherlands News Digest" (in English), 1944; Netherlands News Digest. New York: Netherlands Information Bureau, 1944. (A bi-monthly, serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 15/4)
- Netherlands - News Coverage: "Netherlands News Digest" (in English), 1945; Netherlands News Digest. New York: Netherlands Information Bureau, 1945. (A bi-monthly, serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 15/5)
- Netherlands - Propaganda: Against Germany (in English), 1943; Mein Kampf in Holland, Or, Straight from the Horse's Mouth: By [a Horse in Nazi Uniform]; with a Postcript by Arthur Seyss-Inquart. New York: Netherlands Information Bureau, 1943. (Box 15/6)
- Netherlands - Propaganda: Speeches (in English), 1940; Princess Juliana Speaks. 1940. (Box 15/7)
- Netherlands - Propaganda, Patriotic (in English), 1940; Holland Carries on. New York: Netherlands Information Bureau, 1940. (Box 15/8)
- Netherlands - Reconstruction (in English), 1946; Netherlands News Letter, No. 2. New York: Netherlands Information Bureau, 1946. (Box 15/9)
- Norway - News Coverage, Post-war: "News of Norway" (in English), 1953; News of Norway. Washington, D.C: Norwegian Information Service, 1953. (A weekly, serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 15/10)
- Norway - News Coverage, Post-war: "News of Norway" (in English), 1954; News of Norway. Washington, D.C: Norwegian Information Service, 1954. (A weekly, serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 15/11)
- Norway - News Coverage, Post-war: "News of Norway" (in English), 1955; News of Norway. Washington, D.C: Norwegian Information Service, 1955. (A weekly, serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 15/12)
- Norway - News Coverage, Post-war: "News of Norway" (in English), 1956; News of Norway. Washington, D.C: Norwegian Information Service, 1956. (A weekly, serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 15/13)
- Poland - Atrocities Alleged: Against Germany (in English), 1941-1944; Documents Relating to the Administration of Occupied Countries in Eastern Europe: Extermination of the Polish People and Colonization by German Nationals, Nos. 8 and 9. New York: Polish Information Center, 1941.; The Ghetto Speaks, No. 15. New York: American Representation of the General Jewish Workers' Union of Poland, 1943. (This was a serial publication; only this issue available.); Groth, John. The Camp of Disappearing Men: A Story of the Oswiecim Concentration Camp, Based on Reports from the Polish Underground Labor Movement. New York: Polish Labor Group, 1944. (Box 15/14)
- Poland - Atrocities Alleged: Personal Narratives (in English), 1944; Death at Katyn. New York: National committee of Americans of Polish Descent, 1944. (Box 15/15)
- Poland - Foreign Politics: Territory Questions (in English), 1942-1944; Matuszewski, Ignacy, and Ronald Viner. What Poland Wants. New York, N.Y: National committee of Americans of Polish Descent, 1942.; McKee, John. Poland, Russia, and Our Honor. New York: National Committee of Americans of Polish Descent, 1944. (Box 16/1)
- Poland - News Coverage: German Occupation (in English), 1941; Polish Feature & News Service. New York: Polish Information Center, 1941. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box OS 23/2)
- Poland - News Coverage: Labor Movement (in English), 1942; Poland Fights. New York: Polish Labor Group, 1942. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 16/2)
- Poland - News Coverage: Labor Movement (in English), 1943; Poland Fights. New York: Polish Labor Group, 1943. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 16/3)
- Poland - News Coverage: Labor Movement (in English), 1944; Poland Fights. New York: Polish Labor Group, 1944. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 16/4)
- Poland - News Coverage: Labor Movement (in English), 1945; Poland Fights. New York: Polish Labor Group, 1945. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 16/5)
- Poland - News Coverage: War Effort (in English), 1941; The Polish Review. New York: Polish Review Publishing Co., 1941. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 16/6)
- Poland - News Coverage: War Effort (in English), 1942; The Polish Review. New York: Polish Review Publishing Co., 1942. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 16/7)
- Poland - News Coverage: War Effort (in English), 1942; The Polish Review. New York: Polish Review Publishing Co., 1942. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 16/8)
- Poland - News Coverage: War Effort (in English), 1943; The Polish Review. New York: Polish Review Publishing Co., 1943. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 16/9)
- Poland - News Coverage: War Effort (in English), 1943; The Polish Review. New York: Polish Review Publishing Co., 1943. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 16/10)
- Poland - News Coverage: War Effort (in English), 1943; The Polish Review. New York: Polish Review Publishing Co., 1943. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 16/11)
- Poland - News Coverage: War Effort (in English), 1944; The Polish Review. New York: Polish Review Publishing Co., 1944. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 16/12)
- Poland - News Coverage: War Effort (in English), 1944; The Polish Review. New York: Polish Review Publishing Co., 1944. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 16/13)
- Poland - News Coverage: War Effort (in English), 1944; The Polish Review. New York: Polish Review Publishing Co., 1944. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 17/1)
- Poland - News Coverage: War Effort (in English), 1945; The Polish Review. New York: Polish Review Publishing Co., 1945. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 17/2)
- Poland - Reconstruction: International Affairs (in English), 1955; Festival: 15 Days Remain to the Festival, July 1-14, 1955. Warsaw: Newspaper of the International Preparatory Committee for the 5th World Festival of Youth and Students for Peace and Friendship, 1955.; All Out! It's Warsaw!: Supplement to "Festival." Warsaw: Newspaper of the International Preparatory Committee for the 5th World Festival of Youth and Students for Peace and Friendship, 1955.; Festival: The Festival Begins Tomorow, July 15-30, 1955. Warsaw: Newspaper of the International Preparatory Committee for the 5th World Festival of Youth and Students for Peace and Friendship, 1955. (Box OS 23/3)
- Poland - Reconstruction: Socialism Argument (in English), 1946; Ciołkosz, Adam. The Expropriation of a Socialist Party: The Present Situation of the Socialist Movement in Poland. New York: "Poland fights", Polish labor group, 1946. (Box 17/3)
- Russia - News Coverage (in English), 1942; Carroll, Wallace. Inside Warring Russia: An Eye-Witness Report on the Soviet Union's Battle. New York: United Press Associations, 1942. (Box 17/4)
- Russia - Religion (in English), 1945; The Call of the Russian Church: Report of the General Council of the Russian Orthodox Church, January 31 to February 2, 1945. London: Soviet News, 1945. (17/5)
- United Nations - League of Nations (in English), 1944; Woodrow Wilson Foundation, and Mary Catherine Barton Thomas. Twenty Questions on the League of Nations. New York: Woodrow Wilson Foundation, 1944. (17/6)
- United Nations - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1941; Inter-allied Review: A Monthly Résumé of Documents Relating to the Allied Struggle for Freedom. New York: United Nations Information Office, 1941. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 17/7)
- United Nations - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1942; Inter-allied Review: A Monthly Résumé of Documents Relating to the Allied Struggle for Freedom. New York: United Nations Information Office, 1942. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 17/8)